《大白鲨4：复仇》
住手！
Stop that!
停止什么？ 我什么也没做
Stop what? I'm not doing anything.
噢！\很受伤，你做得对
Ow!\That's hurt, Serves you right.
你能把它剪掉吗？ 我控制不住自己
Will you cut that out? I can't help myself.
你也一样鬼鬼祟祟的 就像你父亲一样
You're as sneaky as your father was.
他一直是偷西红柿的贼
He was the tomato thief of all time.
-我知道你在做什么 -我饿了
- I know what you're doing. - I'm hungry.
让我吃完晚饭 在你吃之前把这些剁碎
Let me finish dinner before you eat it. Chop these.
对不起，伙计们
Sorry, fellas.
哦，妈妈，明晚我们要去 和蒂芙尼一起买圣诞树
Oh, Mom, tomorrow night we're going with Tiffany to buy a Christmas tree.
好的，但是一个小的 小心你的手指
OK, but a small one. Watch your fingers.
不可能，一个大的噢！倒霉！
No way, a big one. Ow! Shit!
-你没事吧？ -是的，它增加了味道
- Are you OK? - Yeah, it adds flavour.
-喂？ -我们不要
- Hello? - We don't want any.
西娅谁？
Thea who?
我知道是西娅?布罗迪 我有几个孙子？
I know it's Thea Brody. How many grandkids do I have?
-我可以自己打电话 -我知道你是个大姑娘
- I can call by myself. - I know. You're a big girl.
-我现在五岁了，奶奶 -我知道你五岁了
- I'm five now, Grandma. - I know you're five.
嗨，孩子 你在下面怎么样？
Hi, kiddo. How're you doin' down there?
我很好，肖恩叔叔 我在上游泳课
I'm fine, Uncle Sean. I'm taking swimming lessons.
-她游得像条鱼 -迈克尔！
- She swims like a fish. - Michael!
-嘿，兄弟 -鱼检查一下
- Hey, bro. - The fish. Check it.
-不可能！你查一下 -我在打电话
- No way! You check it. - I'm on the phone.
-怎么了？ -你奶奶是个奴隶司机！
- What's going on?  - Your grandmother is a slave driver!
-你拿到书了吗？ -是的 谢谢
- Did you get the book? - Yeah. Thanks!
问问大医生他的工作 艰难的生活，你这个巴哈马海滩流浪汉
Ask the big doctor about his job. Tough life, you Bahamian beach bum.
我听到了
I heard that.
-他听到了 -很好
- He heard that. - Good.
嘿，你怎么能早点走？
Hey, how come you get to leave early?
因为我的桌子离门比较近
Cos my desk is closer to the door.
-一个大的 -不，你弟弟不在这里
- A big one. - No, your brother won't be here.
-圣诞快乐！ -圣诞快乐，吉姆
- Merry Christmas! - Merry Christmas, Jim.
-星期四晚上吃蛋酒！ -我们会去的
- Eggnog time Thursday night! - We'll be there.
我们得到一棵大树 所有的旧装饰品
We are getting a big tree for all the old ornaments...
-披风上有长统袜 -为圣诞老人准备饼干和啤酒
- With stockings on the mantle... - And cookies and beer for Santa.
好吧！蒂芙尼，你知道吗 你要嫁给一个多么疯狂的人？
All right! Tiffany, do you realise what a madman you're marrying?
是的，我知道
Yes, I do.
-我要办理登机手续 -好的
- I gotta check in. - OK.
-再见爱你 -再见我也是
- See you. Love you. - Bye. Me, too.
-别迟到！ -是的，是的，是的，是的
- Don't be late! - Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
真糟糕，嗯？
That bad, huh?
我们的无咖啡因饮料用完了， 备用金和申请表
We're out of decaf, petty cash and requisition forms.
我走之前有什么事吗？
Anything to do before I go?
那个人一直在打电话 关于他的训练片
That man keeps calling about his training film.
他不会相信的 我们没有特警队
He won't believe we don't have a SWAT team.
晚安，波利！
Good night, Polly!
友好警察局
Amity Police Department.
别动！
Hold it!
有一个旧的码头堆 在频道里
There's an old dock piling in the channel.
也许它会继续 一直漂到它消失？
Maybe it'll just keep on drifting till it goes away?
-它卡在频道标记上了 -晚安，波莉
- It's stuck on a channel marker. - Good night, Polly.
啊哈它别动！
Uh-huh. It... Hold it!
必须清除 在渔夫回来之前
It has to be cleared before the fishermen come back.
伦尼在哪里？
Where's Lenny?
去本主人家 给牛小费
Out to Ben Master's place. Cow tipping.
给牛小费？
Cow tipping?
说孩子们给他睡觉的牛翻了个身 他们不给牛奶
Says kids tip over his sleeping cows. They're not givin' milk.
好的，我会处理的
OK, I'll take care of it.
布罗迪?威尔副警长 亲自处理
Deputy Brody will take care of it personally.
打电话回家，告诉他们我要迟到了
Call home, tell 'em I'll be late.
-啊哈 -给牛小费！
- Uh-huh. - Cow tipping!
∮ 第一个诺尔 ∮
∮ The first Noel ∮
∮ 天使说 ∮
∮ The angels did say ∮
∮ 对某些可怜的牧羊人来说 ∮
∮ Was to certain poor shepherds ∮
∮ 他们躺在地上 ∮
∮ In fields as they lay... ∮
-不，不，不，不！别动！
- No, no, no, no! Hold it!
别动！大家在一起！ 一起，记得吗？
Hold it! Together, people! Together, remember?
好吧让我们再试一次 二，三
All right. Let's try it again. Two, three.
智者到底在哪里？
Where the hell are the Wise Men?
祝你好运，哈利
Good luck, Harry.
我需要和这帮人在一起
I'm gonna need it with this bunch.
听起来比 当我还是牧羊人的时候
Sounds better than when I was a shepherd.
约瑟夫， 你的长袍到底在哪？
Joseph, where the hell is your robe?
你应该是 穿上戏服！天哪！
You're supposed to be in costume! Jesus!
我在这里！
I'm over here!
好吧，快点离开 准备好了，天使，还有
All right, clear quickly. Ready, angels, and...
很好，各位很好 现在，再一次，诺埃尔，大家
Very good, people. Very good. And now, again, Noel, everyone.
哦，天哪！
Oh, God!
哦，天哪！救命啊！
Oh, God! Help!
帮助我！
Help me!
哦，天哪！帮助我！
Oh, God! Help me!
他的东西 我以为你会想要的
His things. I thought you'd want them.
奶奶！奶奶！
Grandma! Grandma!
我们来了！
We're here!
奶奶？
Grandma?
-妈妈？ -我们来了
- Mom? - We're here.
西娅，下来来吧
Thea, get down here. Come on.
有人在家吗？
Anybody home?
迈克尔
Michael.
妈妈呢？
Where's Mom?
她已经在外面呆了几个小时了
She's been out there for hours.
她怎么样了？
How's she doing?
我们刚从蒂芙尼家来
We've just come from Tiffany's house.
可怜的女孩 医生不得不给她注射镇静剂
Poor girl. The doctors had to sedate her.
-你好，塔夫特夫人 -嗨，甜心
- Hello, Mrs Taft. - Hi, sweetheart.
我没认出你，西娅 你已经长大了
I didn't recognise you, Thea. You're so grown up.
肖恩叔叔死了，你知道的
Uncle Sean is dead, you know.
-他还会回来吗？ -我们稍后再谈
- Will he ever come back? - We'll talk about that more later.
你饿了吗？
Are you hungry?
我吃了个汉堡包 在飞机上
I had a hamburger on the plane.
我们可以做得更好 来一个有趣的骨头三明治怎么样？
We can do better than that. How about a funny bone sandwich?
飞机怎么样？ 很好我有两个棒棒糖
How was the aeroplane ride? Good. I got two lollipops.
-它是为他而来的 -什么？
- It came for him. - What?
它一直在等待， 它为他而来
It waited all this time, and it came for him.
你们一定饿坏了 我来做点意大利烤肉
You guys must be starving. I'll make some fettuccini.
我在做晚饭 你应该坐下来放松
I'm making dinner. You should sit and relax.
真的，艾伦， 没什么可做的了
Really, Ellen, there's nothing left to do.
我要你离开水里
I want you to get out of the water.
什么？
What?
我要你放弃 那份糟糕的工作！
I want you to give up that terrible job!
-你不可能是认真的 -他妈的对
- You can't be serious. - Damn right.
我刚开始
I'm just getting started.
-我不想你靠近水 -妈妈，你很难过
- I don't want you near the water. - Mom, you're upset.
我不想要我的家人 再靠近水的地方
I don't want my family anywhere near the water again.
-从来没有！ -你不能相信那个巫毒
- Never! - You can't believe that voodoo.
鲨鱼不会挑人杀人
Sharks don't pick people to murder.
它选中了肖恩 它杀了你父亲
It picked out Sean. It killed your father.
-爸爸死于心脏病发作 -他死于恐惧
- Dad died from a heart attack. - He died from fear.
妈妈，妈妈，妈妈，妈妈，听我说
Mom, Mom, Mom, Mom, listen to me.
从来没有一个伟大的白人 我们住的地方，永远
There's never been a great white where we live, ever.
是温水他们不喜欢
It's warm water. They don't like it.
你弟弟死了 你父亲死了
Your brother's dead. Your father's dead.
那是一块木头！ 那是一块烂木头！
It was a piece of wood! It was a shitty piece of wood!
迈克尔！
Michael!
他只是在做他的工作
He was just doing his job.
上帝，他能让我笑 有时候
God, he could make me laugh sometimes.
他总是跟在我后面 我们小时候
He was always taggin after me when we were kids.
他一直想这么做 我是什么
He always wanted to do what I was...
嘿，你要去哪里？
Hey, where are you going?
哪里都没有！
Nowhere!
一切 有一个季节，
To everything there is a season,
一个达到所有目的的时刻 在天堂之下
and a time to every purpose under heaven.
出生的时刻 还有死亡的时间
A time to be born and a time to die.
种植的时候，
A time to plant,
一个振作起来的时刻 种植的东西
and a time to pluck up that which is planted.
一个杀戮的时刻，一个治愈的时刻
A time to kill and a time to heal.
崩溃的时刻 一段时间来积累
A time to break down and a time to build up.
哭泣的时刻 是时候开怀大笑了
A time to weep and a time to laugh.
一个哀悼的时刻，一个跳舞的时刻
A time to mourn and a time to dance.
抛石的时刻
A time to cast away stones
还有一次 把石头聚在一起
and a time to gather stones together.
拥抱的时刻
A time to embrace
还有一次 不拥抱”
and a time to refrain from embracing.
嘿，汤姆，等等！
Hey, Tom, wait up!
哦，你会宠坏她的
Oh, you're gonna spoil her.
奶奶就是为了这个
That's what grandmas are for.
你为什么不下来 和我们一起去岛上？
Why don't you come down to the islands with us?
-我我不能那么做 -来吧，妈妈
- I... I can't do that. - Come on, Mom.
-暖和点，和西娅待在一起 -是的！
- Get warm, spend time with Thea... - Yes!
过来，你
Come here, you.
想知道我的想法吗？ 我觉得这是个好主意
Wanna know what I think? I think it's a wonderful idea.
-是的 -拜托，至少考虑一下
- Yes. - Come on, at least consider it.
-走开你不应该一个人 -是的！
- Get away. You shouldn't be alone. - Yes!
-太好了！ -耶！
- Great! - Yay!
-我们可以赶上4点半的渡轮 -今天？
- We can catch the 4.30 ferry. - Today?
-今天 -不，我不能
- Today. - No, I can't.
是的，你可以
Yes, you can.
-甩我，甩我！ -好吧，好吧
- Swing me, swing me! - OK, OK.
哦，我的背！我不能这么做
Oh, my back! I can't do this.
我带她去 哦，天哪，她太重了
I'll take her. Oh, my God, she's too heavy.
帮帮我们，爸爸
Help us, Daddy.
好的，给你坐飞机
OK, here we go. Aeroplane ride.
我知道 我要把你扔下水
I know. I'm gonna throw you overboard.
哦，看！
Oh, look!
哦，嘿， 我一直想骑这种车
Oh, hey, I always wanted to ride one of those.
不可能 鸡肉
No way. Chicken.
妈妈总是说如果上帝是指我们 为了好玩而乘降落伞，
Mom always said if God meant us to ride parachutes for fun,
-我们天生就有票 -我从没说过
- we'd be born with tickets. - I never said that.
是的，你做到了1977年8月
Yes, you did. August 1977.
送苏打水的女士在哪？
Where's the lady who brings the soda?
他们把它们放在大飞机上
They had them on the big plane.
暖瓶里有一些咖啡
There's some coffee in the Thermos.
我太年轻了，不适合喝咖啡 我能开车吗？
I'm too young for coffee. Can I drive?
西娅！
Thea!
有时爸爸把我放在他腿上 让我开吉普车
Sometimes Dad puts me in his lap and lets me steer the Jeep.
有时我让有趣的人 坐在我膝上驾驶飞机
Sometimes I let interesting people sit in my lap and steer the plane.
-哦，真的吗？ -真的
- Oh, really? - Really.
-霍吉？ -是吗？
- Hoagie? - Yeah?
杰克说剩下的你得飞了 你的生活
Jake says you'll have to fly the rest of your life
去偿还你在垃圾场失去的东西
to pay off what you lost at craps.
好消息传得快 我下次再拿回来
Good news travels fast. I'll get it back next time.
怎么会上下颠簸 当没有路的时候？
How come it bumps up and down when there's no road?
是风吹的
The wind does that.
你以前去过巴哈马吗？
You been to the Bahamas before?
-没有 -第一次是最好的
- No. - First time's the best.
那你知道的太多了 什么都不一样
Then you know too much and nothing's the same.
是什么使飞机上下颠簸？
What makes the plane go up and down?
容易的你这样走， 房子也变大了
Easy. You go like this, and the houses get bigger.
然后你就这样走， 房子变小了
Then you go like this, and the houses get smaller.
-你想去兜风吗？ -是的！
- Do you wanna go for a ride? - Yes!
∮ 所以我提议 这个简单的短语 ∮
∮ And so I'm offering this simple phrase ∮
∮ 一岁到92岁的孩子 ∮
∮ To kids from one to 92 ∮
∮ 尽管有人说 ∮
∮ Although it's been said ∮
∮ 很多次，很多方式 ∮
∮ Many times, many ways ∮
∮ 圣诞快乐 ∮
∮ Merry Christmas ∮
∮ 对你来说 ∮
∮ To you ∮
肯尼和三驾马车在比赛 在码头上快点，快点，快点！
Kenny and Tamika are playing on the dock. Hurry, hurry, hurry!
大家都出去！
Everybody out!
-来吧 -肯尼，三驾马车！我回来了！我回家了！
- Come on. - Kenny, Tamika! I'm back! I'm home!
我来帮你 带着袋子，罗密欧
Let me help you with the bags there, Romeo.
-你可以拿重的 -谢谢，伙计
- You can take the heavy ones. - Thanks, buddy.
奶奶！奶奶！
Grandma! Grandma!
你的房间在这里
Your room's in here.
奶奶，看着我！奶奶！
Grandma, watch me! Grandma!
西娅！从那里下去！
Thea! Get down from there!
-奶奶，看着我！ -从那里下去！
- Grandma, watch me! - Get down from there!
-妈妈让我来 -太危险了！别那么做！
- Mommy lets me. - It's too dangerous! Don't do that!
-奶奶，看着我！ -来吧，甜心
- Grandma, watch me! - Come on, sweetheart.
但你总是让我
But you always let me.
今天不行来吧，西娅
Not today. Come on, Thea.
其他的孩子都是
The other kids are.
爸爸，为什么我不能？
Daddy, why can't I?
你听到我说的话了吗？ 快到屋里来！
Did you hear what I said? Come inside the house right now!
-我不想我想荡秋千 -现在你得打开行李
- I don't want to. I wanna swing. - Right now you have to unpack.
我不是故意要开始这一切的 我觉得自己像个奶奶
I didn't mean to start all this. I feel like such a grandma.
来吧我带你到处看看
Come on. I'll show you around.
不！不！把我放下！
No! No! Put me down!
-你能不能别再闹了？ -我想荡秋千！
- Will you stop making a scene? - I wanna swing!
我会没事的，迈克尔
I'll be all right, Michael.
很好我也会
Good. So will I.
她称之为“游手好闲”
She calls it "Tourist on the Loose".
当地政府委托的 去公共海滩
The local government commissioned it for the public beach.
-你把商店忘了 -哦，是的是啊
- You forgot about the store. - Oh, yeah. Yeah.
我们需要牛奶，面包
We need milk, bread...
有一个盛大的揭幕仪式
There's a big unveiling ceremony.
-我们需要啤酒！ -好的，我马上就到！
- We need beer! - OK, I'll be right there!
不错吧？
Pretty good, huh?
是啊
Yeah.
奶奶？
Grandma?
你能不能别再放屁了？
Will you stop fartin around?
迈克尔，他妈的 你在下面干什么
Michael, what the hell you doin' down there, eh?
杰克，别再烦我了
Jake, stop bustin' my chops.
听着，你还记得 他们长什么样？
Listen, you remember what they look like?
外面很硬， 在里面嚼
Hard on the outside, chewy on the inside.
有时候他们会来 有点脏
Sometimes they come with a little grime.
快点，伙计！
Move your ass, man!
啊，宾果！
Ah, bingo!
很好你有多少？
Good. How many you got?
来吧，迈克尔，跟我谈谈 给我一些号码多少？
Come on, Michael, talk to me. Give me some numbers. How many?
-别管我 -你满是狗屎
- Leave me alone. - You're full of shit.
你一整天都在下面， 除了借口什么也不能说
You been down there all day, nothin' to show but excuses.
迈克尔， 你在说“该死的东西”
Michael, you're taggin' the damn things.
我得把女士们分开 首先是先生们
I gotta separate the ladies from the gentlemen first.
不，伙计，不要你走得太慢了 你有两种速度 慢和更慢
No, man, don't. You move too slow. You got two speeds, slow and slower.
别动，杰克 雌性有卵
Hold your water, Jake. The females have eggs.
所以我们要停止一切 分发雪茄？
So we're gonna stop everything and pass out cigars?
我们是为了看 他们去哪里，如何传播
We're being paid to see where they go, how they propagate.
如果我们有足够的资金，我会学习 他们的马达系统，温度
If we had decent funding, I'd study their motor systems, temperature...
我们要做一份像样的报告 给他们一些东西
We'd do a decent report for a change and really give them something.
如果你不理我， 我就能做我的工作了
If you'd leave me alone, I'd be able to do my work.
我知道怎么标记海螺
I know how to tag a damn conch.
-你的阅读很糟糕，伙计 -标签很烂
- Your readings suck, man. - The tags suck.
-不，是我做的 -是我穿的
- No, it's I that made them. - It's I that put 'em on.
-你弄错了 -不，不，不！它们漏了！
- You put 'em on wrong. - No, no, no! They leak!
盲人能找到更多的海螺！
A blind man could find more conch!
你找不到你的屁股 用双手！
You can't find your ass with both hands!
这不公平！你走开，过来 回来一个僵尸，今天是平安夜
That's not fair! You go away, come back a zombie, it's Christmas Eve.
-我们加班是因为你！ -嘿！
- We're working overtime cos of YOU! - Hey!
我对你弟弟很抱歉，伙计
I'm sorry about your brother, man.
好吧，只是 别紧张，好吗？
Well, just... just take it easy, will ya?
杰克
Jake.
来吧，杰克，别 我不想
C'mon, Jake, don't... I don't want...
-哦！把我放下 -我想你了，伙计！
- Oh! Put me down. - I missed you, man!
然后他写了脏话 整个车库
And then he wrote dirty words all over the garage.
他是你爸爸五岁 他和你一样大
He was... your daddy was five. He was your age.
-我快六岁了 -杰克也是
- I'm almost six. - So is Jake.
哦，看看那张脸 好的，做另一个
Oh, look at that face. OK, do the other one.
现在这更接近真实情况了
Now that's closer to the real truth.
哦，你这家伙总是 搞点恶作剧
Oh, you. This guy was always getting into some sort of mischief.
我对此毫不怀疑
I got no doubt about that.
肖恩叔叔曾经坏过吗？ 你打过他吗？
Was Uncle Sean ever bad? Did you ever spank him?
穿得很漂亮，杰克
Sharp shirt, Jake.
嘿，祝你的性生活 像你的衬衫一样忙
Hey, may your sex life be as busy as your shirt.
为什么，谢谢
Why, thank you.
我的茶具！我拿了茶具！
My tea set! I got my tea set!
哦，让我看看！
Oh, let me see!
每一位可爱的女士 应该有一套茶具
Every lovely lady should have a tea set.
它有一个茶壶 还有杯子和碟子
It has a teapot and cups and saucers.
还有一个糖碗 还有一个奶精
And a sugar bowl and a creamer.
我可以放真正的茶吗？ 是的，真茶
Can I put real tea in it? Yes, real tea.
我能做三明治吗？ 对
Can I make sandwiches? Yes.
西娅，我们忘了 圣诞颂歌
Thea, we forgot the Christmas carols.
杂货店的卡罗尔？ 哦，你能阻止它吗？
Carol from the grocery store? Oh, will you stop it?
我想他，妈妈
I miss him, Mom.
-我要你换工作 -妈妈，请不要开始
- I want you to change your work. - Mom, please don't start that.
-你可以教或写 -我现在不会放弃
- You could teach or write... - I'm not gonna quit now.
我只剩下你了我不想 你在水里工作
You're all I have left. I don't want you working in the water.
妈妈，我所做的是绝对安全的
Mom, what I do is perfectly safe.
目前， 我们在收集大蜗牛
At the moment, we're collecting big snails.
杰克和我是科学家 我们差不多是博士了
Jake and I are scientists. We're almost PhDs.
我们知道我们在做什么 没什么好担心的
We know what we're doing. There's nothing to worry about.
哦，太好了
Oh, great.
而且，好吧，我们得挖 沟很深
And, well, we have to dig the ditch really deep...
所以水会一直流下去 我们可以在里面游泳
so the water'll go all the way around and we can swim in it.
你真傻
You're silly.
你知道吗？我们假装 这是白金汉宫
You know what? Let's pretend this is Buckingham Palace.
你将成为狄公主， 我们要和马一起游行
And you'll be Princess Di, and we'll have a parade with horses.
你将乘坐金色的马车， 我们会
And you'll ride in a golden carriage, and we'll...
我可以邀请 灰姑娘去舞会
And I can invite Cinderella to the ball.
她会来的 也坐在金色的马车里
She'll come in a golden carriage, too.
我们可以 饼干，潘趣酒和蛋糕
And we can have cookies and punch and cake.
我可以邀请 查理王子和
And I can invite Prince Charlie and...
叫什么名字 另一个王子？
What's the name of the other prince?
奶奶？奶奶？
Grandma? Grandma?
发生了什么？
What's wrong?
没有什么
Nothing.
哦，我们最好把这事做完 在涨潮之前
Oh, we better get this done before the tide comes in.
逃避是不好的
It's not nice to be evasive.
我妈妈说的 一直对我父亲说
My mother says that to my father all the time.
你好，你们两个！
Hello, you two!
你好
Hello.
我不知道我为什么在这里钓鱼
I don't know why I fish here.
我什么也抓不到
I never catch anything.
水下一定有标志“小心，霍吉在附近”
There must be a sign underwater  "beware, Hoagie's about".
-你开飞机 -驾驶飞机
- You drive the plane. - Flies the plane.
基本上，就像开车一样
Mostly, it's like driving.
那是什么，一个挖掘？
What's that, an excavation?
我们在建一座沙堡， 我们邀请你喝茶
We're building a sand castle, and you're invited for tea.
你知道你为什么 没有野心？
You know why you got no ambition?
-为什么，杰克？ -你的诺曼罗克韦尔生活
- Why is that, Jake? - Your Norman Rockwell life.
诺曼?罗克韦尔？
Norman Rockwell?
那正是 你的问题，我的朋友
That's precisely your problem, my friend.
你不是一个被剥夺了权利的孩子
You weren't exactly a deprived kid.
我不相信 根摇滚雷鬼胡说
I don't buy that roots-rock-reggae bullshit.
剪头发， 你是一套三件套的西装
Cut that hair, you're a three-piece suit.
底线是我们有三个 剩下几个月的工作没有钱了
The bottom line is we got three months left of work and no money.
都花在啤酒上了
Spent it all on beer.
巴哈马渔业部 不完全是诺克斯堡，我的朋友
Bahamian Fisheries Department is not exactly Fort Knox, my friend.
但另一方面，
But, on the other hand,
海军研究办公室， 他们有钱
Office of Naval Research, they've got money.
不，算了吧
No. Forget it.
你什么意思？钱就是钱
What do you mean? Money is money.
-他们把炸弹放在海豚身上 -你在说什么？
- They put bombs on dolphins. - What you talking about?
我认识一个有钱的人 去研究鳗鱼
I know a guy who got money from them to study eels.
很难放炸弹 在鳗鱼上！
It's hard to put a bomb on an eel!
谁弄坏了你的笼子？迈克尔，伙计！
Who rattled your cage? Michael, man!
我们在破坏我们的小木屋 为了拿到学位
We're bustin' our bunghies to get our degrees.
我已经厌倦了天堂的一切
I'm tired of all this paradise shit.
这让我很紧张，伙计
It's getting on my last nerve, man.
威廉看看你，孩子
William. Look at you, boy.
-什么？ -整天看书的精神侏儒
- What? - A mental midget reading all day.
如果平庸使人发胖， 你们都是鲸鱼
If mediocrity were fattening, you'd all be whales.
别再敲了！
Knock off that drummin'!
看看你，孩子 你怎么了？
Look at you, boy. What's wrong with you?
你以为因为你去过 大学你聪明吗？
You think because you been to university you're smart?
我不知道 为什么我要告诉你这些
I don't know why I've told you all this.
有时会说话 对陌生人来说更容易
Sometimes talking to a stranger is easier.
我无法解释 这只是我的感觉
I can't explain it. It's just something I feel.
我总是倾听自己的感受
I always listen to my feelings.
我想我快疯了 噩梦和
I think I'm going crazy. Nightmares and...
可能是意外
Maybe it was an accident.
这不是意外
It was no accident.
我不是说你错了
I'm not saying you're wrong.
我只是说也许 还有其他的可能性
I'm just saying that maybe there are other possibilities.
当它杀死肖恩的时候，我知道 毫无疑问，这是为他而来的
When it killed Sean, I knew with certainty it had come for him.
我就知道！
I knew that!
我知道它来了
I know it's coming.
坐那架飞机要多少钱？
What's it cost to ride on that plane?
水进来了！ 水进来了！
The water's coming in! The water's coming in!
取决于你想去哪里
Depends on where you want to go.
-没关系 -快点！
- Doesn't matter. - Hurry!
-就这样？ -就这样
- Just like that? - Just like that.
哦！哦，不！哦！哦！
Oh! Oh, no! Oh! Oh!
开车！ 我很抱歉？
Take the wheel! I'm sorry?
-开车 -不，我不能
- Take the wheel. - No, I can't.
-当然可以 -我不知道怎么做
- Sure, you can. - I don't know how.
没有人知道
Nobody does till they learn.
你在做什么？
What are you doing?
最好开车 否则我们很快就要游泳了
Better take the wheel or we'll be swimming soon.
哇，别紧张！ 别紧张！
Whoa, take it easy! Take it easy!
轻轻地抱着她 她会自己飞的
Hold her gently. She'll damn near fly herself.
看到了吗？就像开车一样
See? Just like driving a car.
我在哪下车？
Where do I pull off the road?
不，你做得很好 我不让你惹麻烦
No, you're doing fine. I'll keep you out of trouble.
-放松点 -我们要去哪里？
- Relax. - Where are we going?
有一次，我在运送补给 亚马逊河上游
One time, I was flying supplies up the Amazon
当我在丛林里下来的时候
when I came down in the jungle.
-你不告诉我？ -我被猎头抓住了，
- You won't tell me? - I was picked up by head-hunters,
带去见他们的头儿
and taken to their chief.
-你不可能！ -他看着我
- You are impossible! - He looked at me
把我带进他的小屋
and took me in his hut.
在他的小屋里， 有一根很长的杆子
Inside his hut, there was a long pole...
这是什么？
What is all this?
只是一点小东西 我安排让你高兴起来
Just a little something I arranged to cheer you up.
-不，真的 -什么？
- No, really. - What?
-告诉我，这是什么？ -当地的节日
- Tell me, what is all this? - A local festival.
它被称为junkanoo
It's called a junkanoo.
我没听到 上面什么都行，伙计
I'm not hearing anything up here, buddy.
你到底标记了多少个？ 多少？
How many have you tagged, exactly? How many?
迈克尔别再破坏我的小木屋了
Michael... stop busting my bunghie.
是的，你没关系， 但不是为了我，嗯？
Yeah, it's OK for you, but not for me, huh?
别害怕，杰克来了
Have no fear, Jake is here.
我刚撞到了母亲的矿脉 我在数
I just struck the mother lode. I'm counting.
小心点 那套漂亮的设备，伙计
Watch yourself with that fancy equipment, buddy.
这样的电线会 把你的头发竖起来很有趣
Such a live wire'll make your hair stick up funny.
很好，迈克尔威廉？
That's good, Michael. William?
是的，那个男孩没有希望了
Yeah, there's no hope for that boy.
杰克 杰克，那是个笑话
Jake? Jake, that's a joke.
天啊！
Holy shit!
我们这儿有条大鱼，伙计
We got a big fish down here, man.
哦，是吗？有多大？
Oh, yeah? How big?
-天哪！ -当心！
- Jesus! - Look out!
发生了什么？
What's wrong?
艾伦？
Ellen?
天哪！
Jesus Christ!
-艾伦，怎么了？ -什么都没有没有什么我很好
- Ellen, what's wrong? - Nothing. Nothing. I'm fine.
-不，你不是 -我很棒
- No, you're not. - I'm terrific.
快点！
Come on!
放弃吧！
Give it up!
你不能一直这样
You can't keep doing this.
-我不能一直这样 -你答应我喝一杯
- I can't keep doing THIS. - You promised me a drink.
鲨鱼来来往往，艾伦 人们与此无关
Sharks come and go, Ellen. People have nothing to do with it.
-带伞的饮料 -艾伦，放弃吧
- A drink with an umbrella in it. - Ellen, give it up.
踢它屁股
Give it a kick in the arse.
继续你的生活
Get on with your life.
我知道你经历了什么
I know what you've been through.
别担心 噩梦会消失的
Don't worry. The nightmares'll go away.
把眼镜给我，伙计
Give me my glasses, man.
小子，我从没见过 没什么大不了的从未！
Boy, I ain't never seen nothin' so big. Never!
我就在迈克尔旁边 那东西正好从我身边经过！
I was right next to Michael. The thing went right past me!
应该为你而去的，杰克 为什么会这样？
Should've gone for you, Jake. Why did it come up?
-它在温水里干什么？ -有什么区别？
- What's it doing in warm water? - What's the difference?
它只是一条鲨鱼 一条又大又漂亮的鲨鱼
It's only a shark. A big, big, beautiful shark.
这是我们的 不要对任何人说任何话
And it's ours. Don't say anything to anyone.
渔夫会试图杀死它 迈克尔，我们有一个很棒的白人
Fishermen would try to kill it. Michael, we got us a great white.
现在我们要做一些真正的研究
Now we gonna do some real research.
帮我个忙，别说 跟我妈说什么
Do me a favour, don't say anything about this to my mom.
嘿，伙计，我不是故意的， 你知道，张开我的嘴唇，嗯？
Hey, man, I didn't mean to, you know, flap my lips, eh?
所以 所以呢？
So... So?
我对他说:“消毒剂呢？”
I said to him, "Where's the disinfectant?"
他说，“我把它留在城里了”
He said, "I've left it in town."
所以我说， “我们该怎么办？”
So I said, "What are we gonna do?"
所以他说， “我来告诉你我们要做什么
So he says, "I'll tell you what we'll do."
“午饭时回来，所有的 苍蝇会在厨房里”
"Come back at lunchtime, all the flies will be in the kitchen."
上床睡觉吧
Come to bed.
他带她去观光
He took her sightseeing.
好吧，你工作我工作
Well, you work. I work.
她需要有人帮助她 把她的注意力从事情上移开
She needs someone to help her take her mind off things.
我会帮你记下 走开，水手
I'll help you take YOUR mind off things, sailor.
都湿透了
It's soaking.
谢谢您
Thank you.
晚安
Good night.
路易莎
Louisa.
没事的，杰克 我去检查一下桌子
It's OK, Jake. I'll check on the table.
-好吧，一切顺利 -哦，是霍吉！
- OK, everything rides. -Ooh, it's Hoagie!
嘿，来吧，我想看看这个
Hey, come on, I wanna see this.
哦，那是霍吉，好吧
Oh, that's Hoagie, all right.
一切都在进行中
Everything on the line.
-你不是全赌了？ -要么全部要么什么都没有
- You're not betting it all? - All or nothing at all.
-给，你想为我扔吗？ -不！
- Here, do you want to throw for me? - No!
现在准备好了你准备好了吗？
Now get ready. Are you ready?
-我想那很糟糕吧？ -取决于你的观点
- I guess that's bad? - Depends on your point of view.
哦，看看那个过来
Ooh, look at that. Come here.
哦，看看你你看起来太好了！
Ooh, look at you. You look great!
在房子里
It's on the house.
我知道有原因 我买得起这个
I knew there was a reason I could afford this.
谢谢你，雪莉！
Thank you, Shirley!
我父亲常说，“杰克， 你的生活中有两种爱...
My father used to say, "Jake, you got two loves in your life...
“你做什么，和谁在一起”
"what you do and who you're with."
-生日快乐，路易莎 -生日快乐！
- Happy birthday, Louisa. - Happy birthday!
-新年快乐 -新年快乐！
- And a Happy New Year. - Happy New Year!
-新年快乐 -新年快乐
- Happy New Year. - Happy New Year.
膝盖不要虚弱 今晚我请客，孩子
Don't go weak in the knees on me tonight, boy.
你需要 你所有的力量
You're gonna need all the strength you got.
我认识一个单臂钢琴手，
I knew a one-armed piano player,
花了两分钟 跳一分钟华尔兹
took two minutes to play the Minute Waltz.
注意你说话的方式 迈克尔和我即将成名
Watch how you talk. Michael and I are about to be famous.
-告诉他们 -杰克！
- Tell 'em. - Jake!
不谈工作你答应过的
No job talk. You promised.
你答应过的
You promised.
正确的
Right.
你愿意冒险吗 跟我跳支舞，女士？
Would you risk a dance with me, madam?
-你会后悔的 -你也会的我有两只右脚
- You'll be sorry. - So will you. I have two right feet.
很好，我还有两个
That's good, I have two left.
嗯，那是一套
Well, that's a set.
今晚有点安静
A little quiet tonight.
-新年忧郁？ -不，一点也不
- New Year's blues? - No, not at all.
来吧这是我的派对
Come on. It's my party.
他只是迈克尔，他开始 在他睡梦中数数那些该死的海螺
He's just Michael, he's startin' to count them damn conch in his sleep.
请原谅我
Excuse me.
-介意我插手吗？ -拜托
- Mind if I cut in? - Please.
世界会更美好
The world would be a better place
如果更多的儿子跳舞 和他们的母亲
if more sons danced with their mothers.
迈克尔，别撅嘴了
Michael, stop pouting.
你看起来像你以前那样 六个却没有得到你想要的
You look like you did when you were six and didn't get what you wanted.
我喜欢他我喜欢和他在一起
I like him. I enjoy his company.
是啊我不喜欢他 到处追你
Yeah. I don't like him chasing around after you.
我不信任他
I don't trust him.
他不是在追 你太可笑了
He's not chasing. You are being ridiculous.
我一直很讨厌 我很抱歉
I've been a pain in the ass and I'm sorry.
我不会打扰你的 关于你的工作
I'm not gonna bother you about your work.
-你不是痛苦 -让我说完
- You're not a pain. - Let me finish.
我已经排练了一整天了
I've been rehearsing this all day.
肖恩的死差点杀了我 我永远也忘不了，
Sean's death almost killed me. I'll never get over it,
但我拒绝让自己 被一种痴迷所驱使
but I refuse to let myself be run by an obsession.
我不能一直相信 这是故意的
I can't keep on believing it was intentional.
我终于明白了
I finally figured it out.
很好
Good.
就这样，“好”？
That's it, "good"?
我以为你会爆发 香槟
I thought you'd break out the champagne.
不，我很高兴
No, I'm pleased.
来吧给你妈妈看看 你跳得真好
Come on. Show your mother what a good dancer you are.
大家都在哪里？
Where is everybody?
在下面！
Down here!
-克拉伦斯和威廉在哪里？ -我给他们放了一天假
- Where is Clarence and William? - I gave them the day off.
为何？我们还有工作要完成
What for? We got a job to finish.
你为什么要做发射机？
Why are you making a transmitter?
这都是总计划的一部分
It's all part of the master plan.
我们现在要测试一下
We're gonna test it out right now.
我们要了解 它的运动系统，心率
We're gonna learn about its motor systems, its heart rate.
我们要学习 壮丽的动物
We're going to study a magnificent animal
没人知道那么多
no one knows that much about.
太阳下山时，我们出价 向海螺家族告别
As the sun sets, we bid a fond farewell to the family of conch.
我勒个去 你在说什么？
What the hell are you talking about?
我们把它包起来交上来 为什么你的心比我的强？
We wrap it up and hand it in. Why is your heart stronger than mine?
我们什么都没写 直到我们结束
We don't write up anything till we're finished.
我小时候，我父亲说，
When I was a boy, my father said,
“今天什么都不要做 你可以推迟到明天”
"Never do anything today you can put off till tomorrow."
他们海螺明天会在那里
Them conch gonna be there tomorrow.
-当我们拿到补助金的时候，上面说 -不，当我拿到补助金的时候
- When we got the grant, it said... - No, when I got the grant.
-好吧，当我登录时，我 -当我邀请你的时候
- OK, when I signed on, I... - When I invited you.
-我们一起拿到了补助金 -当我们在一起的时候
- We got the grant together. - When we got it together.
我们还有三个月的工作要做 关于这个我们不能写报告
We got three months' work left on this. We can't write a report.
迈克尔，我们这儿有只稀有的鸟 你知道吗？
Michael, we got a rare bird here. You know that, huh?
伟大的白人不会下来 去巴哈马，永远不要
Great white don't come down to the Bahamas, never.
我们有机会吗 就这么游走？
Do we let an opportunity just swim away?
我的名字在报告上
My name's on the report.
半途而废的工作，我找不到 我的博士学位，你也一样
A half-assed job, I don't get my doctorate and neither do you.
我以为我们在计划 一起拥有美好的未来
I thought we were planning a rosy future together.
我也是
So did I.
嘿！嘿！
Hey! Hey!
迈克尔？
Michael?
有人在家吗？
Anybody home in there at all?
你最好脚踏实地 和我们其他人一起
You better beam down to Earth with the rest of us.
如果那条鲨鱼还在水里， 它不会永远在那里
If that shark's still in the water, it won't be there forever.
会有结果的 水太热了
It's gonna figure out the water's too warm.
看着我告诉我你不想 像我一样研究那条鱼
Look at me and tell me you don't want to study that fish as much as I do.
迈克尔？嗯？ 这就是我们训练的目的
Michael? Huh? This is what we trained for.
这就是我们研究的 那些该死的书
This is what we studied them damn books for.
记得， 我的名字也写在那份报告上
Remember, my name goes on that report, too.
对我来说同样重要 就像对你一样，对吧？
It's as important to me as it is to you, right?
好吧， 你喜欢这些该死的蜗牛吗？
All right, you like them damn snails?
好吧，好吧， 我给你做个交易听
All right, all right, I'll make you a deal. Listen.
我们研究那条鲨鱼， 就几天，
We study that shark, just for a few days,
又回来了 敬你可爱的蜗牛
and it's back to your lovely snails.
这很公平，伙计这很公平
Now that's fair, man. That's fair.
来吧，让我尽情享受吧，嗯？
Come on, indulge me with it, eh?
我对电子技术一窍不通
I don't know shit about electronics.
孩子，你什么都不知道 任何事
Boy, you don't know shit about anything.
你该学会了
It's time you learned.
我来教你怎么戴头发， 如何跳舞
I'll teach you how to wear your hair, how to dance.
如何装箱来吧，跟我来
How to box. Come on, follow me.
把你的屁股放下来，伙计
Get your butt down here, man.
这是第三次了 你忘了拿出来
This is the third time you've forgotten to take it out.
-我有很多想法 -你不记得他们什么时候来了吗？
- I got a lot on my mind. - You can't remember when they come?
我的大脑在萎缩
My brain is shrinking...
别给我那个 全神贯注的科学家废话
Don't give me that preoccupied scientist crap.
我正在准备 为了一个大事件！
I'm getting ready for a big event!
我以为艺术家们在工作 和他们的潜意识
I thought artists worked with their subconscious.
为什么这是我的责任？
How come it's my responsibility?
因为
Because.
哦好吧，现在我明白了 你只要解释一下就行了
Oh. OK, now I understand. All you had to do was explain it.
我倒垃圾因为
I take out the garbage... because.
我很高兴我们 弄清楚了
I'm glad we got that straightened out.
我们什么都没有 理顺了
We don't have anything straightened out.
你有点紧张
You're uptight about something.
发生了什么？
What's wrong?
为什么会出什么事？ 我今天休假很愉快，
Why should there be anything wrong? I'm enjoying my day off,
我妻子开始对我大喊大叫 关于垃圾的事
my wife starts yelling at me about the garbage.
我们在争论什么？
What are we arguing about?
我不知道一、
I don't know. I...
我不知道
I don't know.
嘿
Hey.
-不公平，我没有武器 -那就别再靠近了
- No fair, I'm not armed. - Then don't come any closer.
-关掉它关了 -不，我有工作
- Turn it off. Off. - No. I have work.
我一直想做爱 一个愤怒的焊工
I've always wanted to make love to an angry welder.
我什么都没想到 因为我还是个小男孩
I've dreamed of nothing else since I was a small boy.
-把门关上 -啊哈稍后
- Shut the door. - Uh-huh. Later.
-嗯！嗯！ -迈克尔！
- Mmm! Mmm! - Michael!
把门关上！
Shut the door!
你确定你 以前做过吗？
You sure you've done this before?
哦，是的很多次 相信你的杰克叔叔，嗯？
Oh, yeah. Lots of times. Trust your Uncle Jake, eh?
一直都很管用，嗯？
It's always worked, huh?
嗯，呃到目前为止
Well, uh... thus far.
好吧，带我出去
OK, take me out.
再多一点
Little more.
就在那儿！快来！它来了！
There it is! Comin'! It's comin'!
-你记得怎么拉绳子吗？ -是的
- You remember how to pull rope, eh? - Yeah.
对！你抓住他了，伙计！
Yes! You got him, man!
啊！现在是个好时机！
Ah! Now would be a good time!
你看到了吗，伙计？
Did you see that, man?
让我们试着跟着它走
Let's try to follow it.
现在我们要看看杰克叔叔 设备真的对我们有用
Now we're gonna see if Uncle Jake's equipment's really working for us.
迈克尔！
Michael!
-我们的小岛同意你的意见 -我有自己的小岛
- Our little island agrees with you. - I have my own little island.
但是冬天太冷了 我试过一次冬天
But it's so cold in the winter. I tried winter once.
我们到了佛蒙特州伯灵顿
Here we are. Burlington, Vermont.
我飞到纽约去了哦！
I flew a run to New York. Oh!
我左脚有一根骨头 还没有解冻
I have a bone in my left foot that hasn't thawed yet.
-当我还是个小男孩的时候 -顺便说一下，不难想象
- When I was a small boy... - Not hard to imagine, by the way.
……我梦想永远温暖
...I dreamed of always being warm.
你想要什么？ 不管我们上次有什么
What do you want? Whatever we had last time.
请给我两个巴哈马妈妈
Two Bahama Mamas, please.
-留下来我要请假 -你总是请假
- Stay. I'll take time off. - You always take time off.
我喜欢旅行 我会再给飞机划一个缺口
I like to travel. I'll nick the plane again.
-你不会惹麻烦吧？ -如果他不知道就不行
- Won't you get in trouble? - Not if he doesn't find out.
只是跳到 加勒比我们将花几天时间
It's just a hop down to the Caribbean. We'll spend a few days.
一定有很多女士 谁愿意去
There must be a lot of ladies who'd be glad to go.
是的，有，但是
Yeah, there are, but...
我已经累了 单向对话
I've grown tired of one-way conversations.
我有一种无法抗拒的 渴望吻你，艾伦?布罗迪
I have an irresistible urge to kiss you, Ellen Brody.
为什么？
Why?
因为它不会 想想为什么
Because it would not occur to you why.
脸红适合你
Blushing suits you.
-上帝对不起 -没什么好遗憾的
- Lord... I'm sorry. - It's nothing to be sorry about.
不，整件事 整个想法是荒谬的
No, this whole thing... The whole idea is preposterous.
我不这么认为
I don't think so.
-你确定你不需要眼镜吗？ -我是飞行员
- You sure you don't need glasses? - I'm a pilot.
我的视力很好
My vision is perfect.
我们得到了什么？ 九节
What are we getting? Nine knots.
倒霉！我们应该跟上
Shit! We should be keeping up.
-你确定油门开着吗？ -敞开着
- You sure the throttle's open? - Wide open.
来吧，你这个长得太大的金鱼！ 来找杰克叔叔
Come on, you overgrown goldfish! Come to Uncle Jake.
-你认识霍吉多久了？ -什么？
- How long have you known Hoagie? - What?
你认识霍吉多久了？
How long have you known Hoagie?
-他跟这事有什么关系？ -多长时间？
- What's he got to do with it? - How long?
自从他来这里 把它带到右舷！
Since he got here. Bring it to starboard!
他什么时候来的？
When did he get here?
-谁？ -霍吉！
- Who? - Hoagie!
天哪！ 有一天他就在这里，仅此而已
Christ! One day he was just here, that's all.
你对他了解多少？
What do you know about him?
他在追我妈妈
He's after my mother.
-有什么好笑的？ -他对她不够好，是吧？
- What's so funny? - He's not good enough for her, eh?
我同意我会马上送她回家
I agree. I'd send her home right now.
带她过来， 我们走错了路
Bring her about, we're going the wrong way.
我是说，有些飞行员 把毒品飞到这里来
I mean, some of these pilots are flying drugs down here.
-他总是去某个地方 -快带她过来！
- He's always going off somewhere. - Bring her about, now!
-我是！ -快点，伙计，我们又失去他了！
- I am! - Hurry, man, we're losin' him!
-你一定知道些什么 -天哪！
- You must know something. - Christ!
他喜欢赌博， 他喜欢女人，别烦我！
He likes gambling, he likes women, don't bother me!
-他坐包机 -该死的！我们失去了他！
- He flies charter... - Damn! We lost him!
也许你的装备坏了
Maybe your gear crapped out.
也许你被淘汰了， 炫耀你的嘴唇关于霍吉
Maybe you crapped out, flappin' your lips about Hoagie.
也许他已经走了
Maybe he's gone.
好吧，菲什先生
All right, Mr Fish.
我们会回来找你的 明天
We'll come back and find you tomorrow.
他所做的就是吻我！
All he did was kiss me!
-好吧，那是个开始 -什么的开始？
- Well, that's a beginning. - A beginning of what?
不管接下来发生什么
To whatever happens next.
哦
Oh.
我以前以为我能应付这些 一旦我长大了，
I used to think I could handle these situations once I was grown up,
但我甚至不知道 如果他是认真的
but I don't even know if he's serious.
嗯，给点时间，艾伦 看看会发生什么
Mmm, give it some time, Ellen. See what happens.
我的一部分人想 跟他走吧
Well, part of me wanted to go off with him.
我不能
I couldn't.
我不知道他为什么要我
I don't know why he wants me.
也许他很有品味
Maybe he's got good taste.
他还没有 和你这样的女人在一起太久了
He hasn't spent much time with a woman like you.
我不知道他怎么想 或者我的想法这太傻了！
I don't know what he thinks. Or what I think. This is so silly!
我觉得自己太老了，不适合做这件事
I feel too old to be in this thing.
我希望不会我指望着 长久快乐的性生活
I hope not. I am counting on a long, happy sex life.
你说这不礼貌 打断别人
You said it wasn't polite to interrupt people.
是的，我知道
Yes, I did.
-奶奶，该喝茶了 -哦，我差点忘了
- It's time for tea, Grandma. - Oh, I almost forgot.
我没有 我把所有东西都放在房间里了
I didn't. I put everything in my room.
我的泰迪熊和我们一起
My teddy bear's joining us.
迈克尔？
Michael?
迈克尔，怎么了？
Michael, what is it?
没什么，只是个愚蠢的梦
Nothing, just a stupid dream.
隐马尔可夫模型
Hmm.
该睡觉了，花生
Time for bed, peanut.
-哦，不！ -是的爸爸有作业
- Oh, no! - Yep. Daddy's got homework.
-但你昨晚让我去了 -是的，是的
- But you let me last night. - Yeah, yeah.
妈妈在等着看故事
Mommy's waiting to read a story.
-晚安，亲爱的！ -晚安
- Good night, sweetheart! - Good night.
晚安让我们站起来 吹起微风，
Night. Let's put up our feet and shoot the breeze,
或者不管喝啤酒的人做什么
or whatever it is beer drinkers do.
一、呃，我得把 一起做这个报告，妈
I, uh, I got to put together this report, Ma.
杰克说今天不要 你明天能推迟的
Jake says don't do today what you can put off tomorrow.
是的，杰克有很多
Yeah, Jake's got a lot of those.
我过几天就要走了 我不想和你一起不开心
I'm leaving in a few days. I don't want to go with you unhappy.
我没有不高兴
I'm not unhappy.
我看见你和西娅了 你看起来就像你父亲
I saw you and Thea. You looked just like your father.
你还记得什么时候 你们以前常模仿他？
Do you remember when you guys used to imitate him?
妈妈，我得把这件事做完，好吗？
Mom, I gotta get this finished, OK?
-我担心你 -没什么好担心的
- I worry about you. - There's nothing to worry about.
我是你妈妈这是我的工作
I'm your mother. It's my job.
只是因为你是个男人 并不意味着我已经退休了
Just cos you're a man doesn't mean I've retired.
我努力使自己微笑 它是轮到你了
I've worked on MY smile. It's... it's your turn.
这样更好
That's better.
虚张声势，虚张声势！虚张声势，虚张声势！
Blump, blump! Blump, blump!
-虚张声势，虚张声势！虚张声势，虚张声势！ -杰克，住手！
- Blump, blump! Blump, blump!  - Jake, knock it off!
虚张声势，虚张声势好啊， 别想违背我们的协议
Blump, blump. OK, just don't try to renege on our deal.
吃了半天蜗牛， 然后在鲨鱼身上呆半天
Half a day on the snails, then a half a day on the shark.
你还有17分钟，然后我们 去找那条鲨鱼
You got 17 more minutes, then we're gonna go look for that shark.
它是一个大海洋我们可以 用我们的余生去寻找
It's a big ocean. We could spend the rest of our lives looking.
我们会找到他的
We're gonna find him.
我有六个 我会给他们贴上标签然后马上起来
I got about a half a dozen. I'll tag 'em and be right up.
你，呃，听到什么了吗？
You, uh, hearin' anything?
什么都没有再酷一点， 巴哈马的一天是平静而漫长的
Nothin' at all. Just another cool, calm, tickly day in the Bahamas.
就待在四分之一英里内 我有三英里的监控半径
Just stay within a quarter mile. I got a three-mile monitor radius.
三英里之内，那里有很多 是时候把你那丑陋的屁股照上去了
Within three miles, there's plenty of time to beam your ugly ass up.
迈克尔，我抓住他了
Michael, I got him.
他向你走来 你最好现在就出去
He's comin' towards you. You better get out now.
好吧，我来了，我来了
All right, I'm comin', I'm comin'.
倒霉！
Shit!
杰克
Jake!
迈克尔！迈克尔！
Michael! Michael!
迈克尔！
Michael!
迈克尔，怎么了？ 迈克尔，你能听见我说话吗？
Michael, what's goin' on? Michael, can you hear me?
迈克尔！迈克尔，你能听见我说话吗？
Michael! Michael, can you hear me?
迈克尔！
Michael!
狗娘养的！哦，该死！
Son of a bitch! Oh, shit!
天哪！
Jesus Christ!
啊！
Ah!
休斯敦大学！
Uh!
在那边！
It's over there!
倒霉！把棒子拿过来， 我们继续下去
Shit! Get the bang sticks, we're goin' down.
-他们不好 -再来一个！
- They're no good. - Get another one!
快点，快点！迈克尔！
Come on, come on! Michael!
-把他扶起来！小心他的手臂！ -把他轻轻地放下！
- Get him up! Watch his arm! - Lay him down gently!
我们需要止血带 为了止血
We need a tourniquet to stop his bleeding.
-试试这个！ -把湿衣服脱了
- Try this! - Get the wet suit off.
冷静点，不要担心
Keep cool, don't worry.
迈克尔，你好吗？ 我想他可能很震惊
Michael, how are you? I think he may be in shock.
克拉伦斯，快走！
Clarence, move it!
嘿，嘿，嘿！ 嘿，你在做什么，伙计？
Hey, hey, hey! Hey, what you doin', man?
没人下水 直到我们知道那条鱼在哪里
No one goes in the water till we know where that fish is.
你从马上摔下来， 你马上回来
You fall off the horse, you get right back on.
见鬼，什么废话 你在说什么？嗯？
Hell, what kind of bullcrap you talkin'? Huh?
-任何人都在水里，是我 -杰克，我要下去了
- Anybody's in the water, it's me. - Jake, I'm gonna go down.
好吧，那么卡拉的演唱会呢？ 快到时间了，伙计
All right, so what about Carla's gig? It's almost time, man.
迈克尔，我不能让你 回去吧
Michael, I can't just let you go back down.
我吓得屁滚尿流
I'm scared shitless.
我到底在做什么 如果我不能回到水里？
What the hell do I do if I can't go back in that water?
好吧，小心点
All right, be careful.
克拉伦斯，上那个小屋 让我们注意一下
Clarence, get up on that shack. Give us some lookout.
-我希望他知道他在做什么 -他要做什么
- I hope he knows what he's doing. - He's doin' what he's got to do.
杰克，你是不是有关于鲨鱼的消息吗？
Jake, are you gettin' anything on the shark?
不，一切都很酷
No, everything's cool.
我在想昨天的事 可能是个错误
I'm thinkin' about yesterday. It's probably a mistake.
-他饿了你看起来很好吃 -但为什么只有我？
- He was hungry. You look tasty. - But how come only me?
-也许他只是喜欢吃白肉 -你是个有趣的人，杰克
- Maybe he just like white meat. - You're a funny guy, Jake.
天哪！
Jesus!
是关于艺术的 我今天想说的话
It is about art that I wish to speak today.
艺术的原材料 围绕着我们，
The raw material of art surrounds us all,
在网中捕捉每一个 我们每个人
catching in the net that each and every one of us casts
融入生活的潮流
into the current of life.
-但这需要艺术 -他们到底在哪里？
- But it takes the art... - Where the hell are they?
他们会来的
They'll be here.
-我可以坐香蕉船去吗？ -嘘！
- Can I go on the banana boat? - Shh!
玛格丽特要走了 她和她妈妈在一起
Margaret's going. She's with her mother.
-好的 -哦，孩子！哦，孩子！
- OK. - Oh, boy! Oh, boy!
-西娅，你要小心 -我会的，我会的！
- Thea, you be careful. - I will, I will!
-西娅！ -没关系香蕉船很有趣
- Thea! - It's OK. Banana boats are fun.
哦，我们应该很幸运 我真希望我们和她一起玩
Oh, we should be so lucky. I wish we were out with her playin'.
玛格丽特，等我！
Margaret, wait for me!
“说到重点，伙计 就像我妻子现在说的
"Get to the point, man," as my wife now says.
好啊总之，艺术就是油脂 为了生命之轮
OK. Well, in short, art is grease for the wheel of life.
今天我们很荣幸 奉献一件艺术品
Today we are privileged to dedicate a work of art.
卡拉?布罗迪，
Carla Brody,
一个名声越来越大的艺术家，
an artist of growing reputation,
被委托表达 我们永久的生活方式
was commissioned to express our way of life in permanent form...
向世界展示我们所知道的 就在这个海滩上
to show the world what we all know right here on this beach.
巴哈马更好
That it is better in the Bahamas.
-当然 -女士们先生们，卡拉?布罗迪！
- Absolutely. - Ladies and gentlemen, Carla Brody!
谢谢你，威瑟斯彭局长， 威瑟斯彭太太
Thank you, Commissioner Witherspoon, Mrs Witherspoon.
西娅！
Thea!
哦，天哪！
Oh, my God!
西娅！
Thea!
住手！回来！把她带回来！
Stop! Come back! Bring her back!
哦，天哪！
Oh, my God!
住手！西娅！西娅！
Stop! Thea! Thea!
西娅！
Thea!
有人做点什么！
Somebody do something!
西娅！
Thea!
哦，不！天哪！
Oh, no! My God!
-妈妈！妈妈！ -西娅！
- Mommy! Mommy! - Thea!
快去找医生！ 快叫医生来！
Somebody get a doctor! Get a doctor now!
迅速地！
Quickly!
-对不起，我想你了 -你去哪儿了？
- I'm sorry I missed you. - Where have you been?
怎么了？怎么搞的？
What's the matter? What happened?
西娅被鲨鱼袭击了
Thea was attacked by a shark.
哦，天哪
Oh, my God.
医生说她应该没事 她很震惊
The doctor said she should be OK. She's in shock.
亲爱的？亲爱的？
Sweetheart? Sweetheart?
我很抱歉 我早该知道的上帝啊
I'm so sorry. I should've known. Jesus.
应该知道什么吗？
Should've known what?
-我们试图跟踪他 -的
- We tried to keep track of him. - Of...
鲨鱼
The shark.
-你知道吗？ -是的以为它消失了
- You knew? - Yeah. Thought it went away.
-在我后面 -她可能已经被杀了你知道吗？
- Came after me. - She could've been killed. You knew?
你没有告诉我们？ 你让你妈妈想
And you didn't tell us? You let your mother think...
她在哪里？
Where is she?
-你怎么能这么做？ -我妈妈在哪里？
- How could you do that? - Where's my mother?
-我妈妈在哪里？ -你为什么不告诉我们？
- Where's my mother? - Why didn't you tell us?
-杰克在哪里？ -你为什么不告诉我们？
- Where's Jake? - WHY DIDN'T YOU TELL US?
迈克尔！
Michael!
杰克
Jake!
-杰克！ -什么？
- Jake! - What?
快点！我需要你！快点！
Come on! I need you! Hurry up!
霍吉！你看到我们的船了吗？
Hoagie! Did you see our boat?
-我刚到这里 -我妈妈拿走了
- I just got here. - My mother took it.
-我希望她是个好水手 -一条鲨鱼袭击了西娅
- I hope she's a good sailor. - A shark attacked Thea.
她去追那该死的东西
She went after the damn thing.
-她在追吗？ -是的，我们得阻止她
- She's gone after it? - Yeah, we gotta stop her.
在那里面？ 在浴缸里呆一整天
In that? Lt'll take all day in that bathtub.
有更好的主意吗？
Got a better idea?
我会用无线电通知她的位置
I'll radio her position.
救援船会来接她， 所以不要担心
The rescue boats will pick her up, so don't worry.
她会没事的
She'll be fine.
她永远也找不到那条该死的鲨鱼 我们不能
She'll never find that bloody shark. We couldn't.
它会找到她的 什么意思？
It'll find her. What do you mean?
她说要来了
She said it was coming.
-你什么意思？ -你知道什么？
- What do you mean? - What do you know?
她认为鲨鱼 他杀了马丁和肖恩
She thinks the shark that killed Martin and Sean
正在跟踪家人
is following the family.
嘿，他不说话 关于我们的鲨鱼，嗯？
Hey, he's not talkin' about our shark, eh?
你什么时候做 你不是开飞机的人吗？
What do you do when you're not flying people?
我送洗好的衣服
I deliver laundry.
等等那是什么？ 让我们看看
Hold on. What's that? Let's have a look.
哦
Oh.
外面是一片大海
It's a big ocean out there.
这东西能不能再快一点？
Can't this thing go any faster?
再快一点，这个东西 飞翔的翠鸟
Any faster, this thing'll be a flying Cuisinart
我们会被抛在脑后
and we'll be diced into oblivion.
来接我， 你这狗娘养的
Come and get me, you son of a bitch.
她来了 她就在那儿
There she is. That's her right there.
我就是这么想的吗？
Is that what I think it is?
-妈妈 -等等！
- Mom... - Hold on!
哦！
Oh!
托马斯，你在吗？ 这里是零阿尔法爸爸
Thomas, you there? This is Zero-Papa-Alpha here.
霍吉，你在哪儿？
Hoagie, where are you?
距离翡翠公园东南12英里 寻找海王星的愚蠢
12 miles southeast of Emerald Key. Look for Neptune's Folly.
我需要两艘快艇 谁能杀死鲨鱼 一条大鲨鱼
I need two boats fast and somebody who can kill a shark, a big one.
你在做什么？ 练习着着陆
What're you doing?  Practising landing.
伙计们，抓紧你们的袜子
Hang on to your socks, lads.
等待！你确定你知道 怎么做？
Wait! You sure you know how to do this?
当然不是！ 你认为我是什么样的飞行员？
Of course not! What kind of pilot do you think I am?
-天哪！ -见鬼，还不错
- Christ! - Hell, not half bad.
出去，我会让它忙个不停的
Get out, I'll keep it busy.
不，它会来接飞机的 电磁脉冲
No, it'll come for the plane's electromagnetic impulse.
滚出去！
Get the bloody hell out!
迈克尔！
Michael!
该死的乘客！你还是老样子 抱怨，抱怨
Damn passengers! You're all the same. Complain, complain...
哦，该死！
Oh, shit!
霍吉！
Hoagie!
霍吉！霍吉！
Hoagie! Hoagie!
你为什么来这里？
Why'd you come out here?
-你为什么带他来？ -妈妈，妈妈！
- Why did you bring him? - Mom, Mom!
-你为什么要坐船？ -它一直在来！
- Why'd you take the boat? - It kept coming!
-你没有意识到吗？ -没有别的事可做
- Didn't you realise? - There was nothing else to do.
-你不应该这么做的 -我想告诉你
- You shouldn't have done it. - I tried to tell you.
我试过了
I tried.
嘿！ 看在上帝的份上，帮我一把！
Hey! Give me a hand, for Christ's sake!
-霍吉！ -你是怎么做到的，伙计？
- Hoagie! - How the hell did you do that, man?
-相信我，这不容易 -把他扶起来
- It wasn't easy, believe me. - Get him up.
你还好吧，伙计？
You all right, man?
-哦！该死的 -开始吧！
- Oh! Bloody hell. - Get it started!
-那东西上的气！ -你还活着！
- The breath on that thing! - You are alive!
让我们离开这里， 埃伦?布罗迪哦！
Let's get out of here, Ellen Brody. Oh!
很好，这个东西还在用
Good, this thing's still working.
那是你的引擎，伙计 我去看看
That's your engine, pal. I'll have a look.
哦，妈的，他离我们很近，伙计
Oh, shit, he's close, man.
-那是什么声音？ -鲨鱼的心跳
- What is that sound? - The shark's heartbeat.
霍吉，试着说完 迈克尔，帮我个忙，我有个主意
Hoagie, try to finish. Michael, gimme a hand, I got an idea.
我们在这里取水 艾伦，从这里开始抽
We're taking water down here. Ellen, start pumping here.
艾伦！把舱底泵拿来！
Ellen! Get the bilge pump!
取出无线电发射器 把它挂在频闪上
Take the radio transmitter out and hook it to the strobe.
-我们得发动引擎！ -就这么做！
- We gotta get the engine started! - Just do it!
我们要喂那个大男孩 一顿他赢了的饭
We're gonna feed that big boy a meal he won't forget.
你最好做点好事 我们的水管坏了
You better have something good going. We've got a rotten hose.
有一个备用的 你想怎么处理这个？
There's a spare one. What you wanna do with this?
我在操做接收器我们明白了 在那个混蛋里面引爆它
I'm riggin' the receiver. We get it inside that bastard and set it off.
我得到了它我们在上面装了天线， 我们可以把他吓跑
I got it. We rig an antenna on this, we can shock the hell out of him.
正确的！你在重新学习
Right! You're learning.
他越来越近了！
He's getting closer!
他们一生都在寻找 食物，他们不在乎它是什么
They spend their lives looking for food, they don't care what it is.
也许他消化不良 他吃了我的飞机！
Maybe he's got indigestion. He's eaten my plane!
他要的不是食物
It's not food he's after.
迈克尔，打开开关 我需要一个测试
Michael, turn on your switch. I need a test.
-有人告诉你你疯了吗？ -一直如此
- Anybody tell you you're nuts? - All the time.
如果它有反应 对于外部电脉冲，
If it responds to external electrical impulse,
它可能对里面的一个有反应，迷惑他，把他逼疯
it might respond to one inside, confuse him, drive him crazy.
好吧，一个测试很好
OK, a test... Good.
你最好上来！ 心跳停止了！
You'd better get up here! The heartbeat's stopped!
倒霉
Shit.
要么他走了 或者你的装备又坏了
Either he's gone or your gear's crapped out again.
那是最牛的我的设备 不要废话他会回来的
That's bull. My equipment don't crap out. He'll be back.
把船钩给我
Get me the boat hook.
也许他心脏病发作了 人类富含胆固醇
Maybe he had a heart attack. Humans are full of cholesterol.
-把那个给我 -妈的！他在哪里？
- Give me that. - Shit! Where is he?
把电话给我，迈克尔 就在那里
Give me that line, Michael. Right there.
他来了！
There he is!
艾伦，试试引擎
Ellen, try the engine.
艾伦！试着发动引擎！
Ellen! Try to start the engine!
狗娘养的 让我们离开这里
Son of a bitch. Let's get out of here.
不，太晚了，霍吉 给我一个硬端口
No, it's too late, Hoagie. Give me a hard port.
正确的！
Right!
给，给我 不！没时间了！
Here, give me that. No! No time for that!
杰克你不能出去 没有线！
Jake! You can't go out there without a line!
保持稳定 它会回来的！
Keep it steady. It's gonna come back!
该死的东西消失了他走了！
Damn thing's disappeared. He's gone!
杰克
Jake!
我们喝太多水了 它会使发动机熄火
We're taking too much water. It'll stop the engine.
艾伦，开车 我们必须超越它艾伦！
Ellen, take the wheel. We've got to outrun it. Ellen!
-那东西能用吗？ -它会起作用的
- That thing gonna work? - It'll work.
如果杰克这么说，它会的 这项指控会把它逼疯的
If Jake says so, it will. This charge will drive it crazy.
亲爱的耶稣， 我们直接去了！
Sweet Jesus, we're headed straight for it!
艾伦，过来！
Ellen, come about!
我们会成功的！ 等等！
We're gonna hit it! Hold on!
等等！
Hold on!
笑一笑，你这个狗娘养的！
Smile, you son of a bitch!
-迈克尔！ -过来
- Michael! - Come over here.
迈克尔！
Michael!
没关系！我没事！
It's all right! I'm OK!
有人吗？在这里！
Anybody there? Over here!
杰克
Jake!
迈克尔，你有空吗？
Michael, you got a minute?
是杰克！
It's Jake!
狗娘养的！
Son of a bitch!
天哪，杰克
Jesus, Jake.
你怎么花了这么长时间，伙计？
What took you so damn long, man?
你还活着干什么？
What the hell are you doing alive?
我告诉过你杰克叔叔 设备不用废掉，是吧？
I told you Uncle Jake's equipment don't crap out, eh?
你不会做什么的 像死在我身上一样愚蠢，是吗？
You're not going to do something stupid like die on me, are you?
不，伙计我太刻薄了
No, man. I'm way too mean for that.
所以从现在开始， 我们要研究蜗牛，嗯？
So from now on, we're going to study snails, eh?
是啊
Yeah.
今年夏天来和睦家吧
Come to Amity this summer.
我们会到的 你一定要让他们来
We'll be there. You make sure they come.
我会的 奶奶，我会想你的
I will. I'll miss you, Grandma.
上车，艾伦?布罗迪 你会误机的
Get in, Ellen Brody. You'll miss your plane.
-再见，奶奶！ -好的
- Goodbye, Grandma! - OK.
-小心点 -好的再见
- Be careful. - OK. See ya.
-好好照顾杰克 -我会的
- Take good care of Jake. - I will.
你会没事吧？
You gonna be OK?
-是的 -好的
- Yeah. - OK.
当我回来的时候， 提醒我告诉你时间
When I come back, remind me to tell you about the time
我带了一百个修女去了内罗毕
I took a hundred nuns to Nairobi.
他们在那里， 100个修女，弹吉他
There they were, 100 nuns, playing guitars
唱着“山还活着” 伴随着音乐的声音
and singing, "The hills are alive with the sound of music."
突然间， 一个走到我面前，她说，
Then suddenly, one comes up to me and she says,
“烟来了 从发动机上”
"There's smoke coming from the engine."
但我从来没有 认真对待他们，
But I never took them seriously,
直到他们都开始唱歌:“我的上帝离你更近一点”
until they all started singing "Nearer My God to Thee."